<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Peter LaBau Banjo]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Peter LaBau Banjo]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/peter-labau-banjo/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 20:28:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/peter-labau-banjo/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bio]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Bio</h1><p>Peter LaBau has been playing the banjo (and dobro and guitar) for going on 50 years, and is hard pressed to refute the old saying “the first 30 years are the hardest”. Initially entranced by the plectrum style banjo playing of local kiddie show host Ranger Andy as a five year old, Peter was lured away by the guitar at the age of ten, and for several years studied that instrument at the Hartt School of Music in Hartford, CT.  Peter dove into learning the 5-string banjo in 1973, after finally surrendering to the siren call of banjo he heard from the Kingston Trio, the Beverly Hillbillies theme song, the theme from the movie “Deliverance” and so much other music coming out of the folk boom of the 60’s and 70’s. Not knowing anyone who actually played the instrument (beyond Ranger Andy, who wasn’t interested in teaching, probably because by that time he had died), it was tough sledding trying to learn from records, and the few instructional methods of that time. Finally exposed to others who played while in college in Vermont, Peter developed a proficiency with Bluegrass banjo, playing in a number of bands in New England through the later 1970’s. In 1980, Peter heard Clarke Buehling playing “Classic Style” banjo, and was immediately smitten. That started a parallel journey along with bluegrass playing into that style of banjo that was popular in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Peter has performed on stages on both sides of the Atlantic, has appeared on TV, radio, and with theater orchestras, and is currently a member of the Charlottesville-based “Bent Mountain Trio”. He lives an teaches out of his studio barn in Stoney Point, just north of Charlottesville. </p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/bfdb0f5eb59381777da4b3790e2f4f46d8c3210b.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/peter-labau-banjo/bio/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7957a4f0-b5ee-4931-844f-c3b9b4f177cd</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 20:28:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Peter LaBau Banjo is my new site for showcasing and sharing my 40+ year journey with the 5-string banjo. Here you'll find photos, reviews, videos, commentary, CDs, and links to relevant sites of interest to lovers of the banjo. </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/peter-labau-banjo/851e961c-aa31-41fd-a187-22a6c9711cd1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">851e961c-aa31-41fd-a187-22a6c9711cd1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 20:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>